<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://docbook.org/xml/5.1/rng/docbook.rng" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://docbook.org/xml/5.1/sch/docbook.sch" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<chapter xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
    version="5.1">
    <title>Introduction</title>
    <para>We very often read articles or hear people speaking about precision farming and
        agriculture automation. However, we do have the feeling that, most of the time, agriculture
        automation projects mainly consists in improving the traditional way of doing things. As an
        example, the majority of farmers continue to use chemicals to control pests and weeds, and
        many of them continue to work huge areas of crops. These chemicals are not only expensive,
        but also toxic to our environment and our health.</para>
    <para>Large areas of monoculture favour the development of diseases and the proliferation of
        insect pests, while reducing their predators. This way of working seriously damages
        biodiversity, the environment and the climate.</para>
    <para>If we want to continue to live on our planet, preserve our environment and our health, we
        must quickly change the way we do things. However, changing our habits does not necessarily
        mean returning to the Middle Ages. We can use technology intelligently to help us in our
        change and ease our life.</para>
    <para>That's why we decided to design an open source robotics platform, called <emphasis>gribot</emphasis>, that
        everyone should be able to build with a minimum of help. To this end, we publish all
        schemas, models and software completely free of charge under GNU General Public License. We
        believe that the free publication of our work will accelerate the diffusion of the robotic
        gribot platform and thus reduce the impact on the environment.</para>
    <para>We are firmly convinced that the future of agriculture depends on a reduction in the size
        of farms, cultivated plots, an increase in the diversity of cultivated plants, a decrease in
        the number of head of livestock, a serious reduction in the consumption of non-renewable
        energy, etc.</para>
    <para>The objective of the <emphasis>gribot</emphasis> platform is to help the farmer, not to
        replace him, in his daily tasks, such as mowing grass in crops, weeding small cultivated
        areas, planting, harvesting, and many other tasks that we have not yet thought of.</para>
    <para>This project is very ambitious in many ways. For example, some activities that we would
        like to automate are still in the research stage or not even studied yet. Agriculture may
        not always be a very sexy subject, but it feeds the world's population and therefore
        deserves a project of this ambition.</para>
    <para>Although our target is agriculture, the <emphasis>gribot</emphasis> platform is not
        exclusively limited to this market. Grass mowing, for example, involves many other
        activities such as roadside maintenance, grassy surfaces in industrial areas, etc. Any idea
        for using <emphasis>gribot</emphasis> is welcome.</para>
    <section>
        <title>What gribot means ?</title>
        <para>Perhaps you've wondered what <emphasis>gribot</emphasis> means. It is not a fantastic
            animal from the imagination of J. K. Rowling and encountering Harry Potter.</para>
        <para>We were looking for a short name and not yet used as a domain name. After some time of
            braistorming, cutting and mixing the words agriculture and robot, we found a<emphasis
                role="bold">gri</emphasis>culture ro<emphasis role="bold">bot</emphasis>, which
            gives gribot.</para>
    </section>
    <section>
        <title>Project organization</title>
        <para>The <emphasis>gribot</emphasis> initiative is built around a multicultural community
            of people motivated to improve our environment and to see this project succeed. All
            members of this community are passionate volunteers.</para>
        <para>In the long run, we hope to be able to sell parts, kits and even complete robots to
            people who would not have the possibility to build everything themselves.</para>
        <para>We will also consider collaborating with fablabs or collective workshops, in order to
            allow everyone to acquire a <emphasis>gribot</emphasis> robot.</para>
    </section>
</chapter>

