<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://docbook.org/xml/5.1/rng/docbook.rng" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://docbook.org/xml/5.1/sch/docbook.sch" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<chapter xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
    xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" version="5.1">
     <title>Introduction</title>
     <para>In the requirement document, we described <emphasis>what</emphasis> the gribot platform
        should do and the goal to reach. The specification document describes how we will do it.
        This document is much more technical as it contains many subjects such as:</para>
    <para>
        <itemizedlist>
            <listitem>
                <para>Analysis</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>Calculations and dimensioning</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>Technology choices</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>etc.</para>
            </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
    </para>
    <para>During the preparation of the specification document, it is often necessary to revisit the
        requirements definition document to clarify a point, and sometimes even to modify an unclear
        specification, or to add one to clarify the situation.</para>
    <para>In this document, specification will be split into two main categories:</para>
    <para>
        <variablelist>
            <varlistentry>
                <term>Platform specification</term>
                <listitem>
                    <para>These specification concerns the whole <emphasis>gribot</emphasis>
                        platform, such as general architecture, software to use, technology to use,
                        etc. In other word, all elements common to the <emphasis>gribot</emphasis>
                        robot family. As an example, the navigation system concerns the whole
                        platform.</para>
                </listitem>
            </varlistentry>
            <varlistentry>
                <term>Robot specification</term>
                <listitem>
                    <para>These specification concerns only one robot in the family, performing a
                        specific function. It contains only those elements that are useful for this
                        robot. As an example, the mower cutterbar does not concern the weeding
                        robot.</para>
                </listitem>
            </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
    </para>
    <para>The following chapters will describe these different specifications.</para>
</chapter>

