<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://docbook.org/xml/5.1/rng/docbook.rng" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://docbook.org/xml/5.1/sch/docbook.sch" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<chapter xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
    xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" version="5.1">
     <title>Introduction</title>
    <para>We very often talk about precision farming and agricultural automation. However, most of
        these projects consist in improving the traditional way of doing things, without radically
        changing it. As an example, grass management in crops such as vines, fruit trees, or plot
        ends is done in a very traditional way: with a tractor and mower or gyro mower, and with
        weed killers for areas that are not or not easily accessible by machines. The same problem
        can be found in the maintenance of roadsides or large non-agricultural grassy areas.</para>
    <section>
        <title>Objectifs du robot tondeuse</title>
        <para>This mower robot is part of a sustainable development approach. The objectives
            are:</para>
        <para>
            <itemizedlist>
                <listitem>
                    <para>Eliminate the use of polluting herbicides that are harmful to health and
                        nature.</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>Reduce CO<subscript>2</subscript> emissions by not using fossil and
                        non-renewable fuels.</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>Reduce operating costs.</para>
                    <para>In order to be able to quickly integrate into a sustainable development
                        logic, the robot's plans and software are distributed under the GNU General
                        Public License (GPL), including the elements we buy ready-made, such as
                        engines, LIDAR, electronic circuits, etc. that are under the manufacturer's license<footnote>
                            <para>These elements may be under proprietary license.</para>
                        </footnote>.</para>
                    <para>The robot can also be sold completely assembled, or as a kit either
                        complete or partial. The partial kit includes, for example, elements
                        machined specifically for the robot.</para>
                    <para>All plans and software are freely available on the Internet.</para>
                </listitem>
            </itemizedlist>
        </para>
    </section>
</chapter>

