<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://docbook.org/xml/5.1/rng/docbook.rng" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://docbook.org/xml/5.1/sch/docbook.sch" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<chapter xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
    xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" version="5.1">
     <title>Mowing</title>
     <para>As mentioned above, the mower robot will be the first element of the
            <emphasis>gribot</emphasis> robotic platform. There are several reasons for this choice:
        grass care in crops is unproductive, time-consuming and uses a lot of non-renewable energy
        unnecessarily. We estimated that maintaining the grass in one hectare of fruit trees
        consumed about 100 liters of fuel oil per year and required almost a week's work.</para>
    <para>We also noticed that such a robot would be useful in many other places outside
        agriculture, such as roadside maintenance, grass mowing in industrial plots, community plot
        maintenance, in short, any grassy surface, not always very flat, requiring regular
        mowing.</para>
    <para>The requirement for the mower robot are listed below.</para>
    <para>
        <itemizedlist>
            <listitem>
                <para>The robot should not exceed 60cm in width, in order to easily slip between
                    fruit trees or vines.</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>The height of the robot should not exceed 30 to 40 cm in order to be able to
                    slip under fruit trees or vines.</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>The robot should be able to maintain 20,000 m<superscript>2</superscript>
                    (2Ha).</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>The robot's working surface must under no circumstances be made by burying a
                    wire, as is done for lawn care robots. An electronic means, such as GPS or other
                    positioning system, will always be preferable.</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>The robot must be able to move easily on irregular surfaces that may have
                    holes about ten centimeters deep.</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>The robot must be able to overcome obstacles of at least 10 cm in
                    height.</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>The robot should have an autonomy of at least 4 hours.</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>The robot must be able to detect obstacles and calculate its trajectory in
                    order to avoid them.</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>The robot must implement a strategy to optimize its work in order to save its
                    battery. A completely random trajectory is strongly discouraged.</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>The robot must be able to climb slopes of 45°.</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>Users and animals must not be allowed to come into contact with moving parts
                    of the robot. For example, it is possible to detect a presence in the robot
                    environment and to stop any moving parts.</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>The robot must stop when someone approaches too close.</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>Cutting elements (e.g. mower knives) must stop if the machine tilts too
                    much.</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>The machine must stop completely and go into alarm if it overturns.</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>The machine must stop completely and go into alarm if it is blocked.</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>The robot must be able to be controlled remotely, for example by means of a
                    mobile terminal (smart phone).</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>The robot must be protected against unauthorized remote access.</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>Robot ownership must be tracked: if the owner sell his robot to someone else,
                    a mechanism has to be put in place to track this transaction. All access right
                    and ownership parameters have to be transmitted to the new owner.</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>The robot must be able to be remotely activated or deactivated.</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>The robot alarms must be transmitted to the mobile control terminal.</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>The work surface and the zones to be avoided must be easily and if possible
                    remotely configured, for example by drawing on a map.</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>The robot must have a charging station.</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>The robot must be able to return to its charging station by itself when its
                    battery is discharged. The order of return to the charging station must take
                    into account the battery capacity and the energy required for the return
                    journey.</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>When the robot is connected to its charging station, it stops all unnecessary
                    electrical consumers.</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>When the robot's battery is recharged, it must be able to automatically return
                    or it has abandoned its work.</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>The robot must have an autonomous charging station, powered by solar panels or
                    a wind turbine, for example.</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>The charging time of the robot battery should not exceed 4 hours when the
                    charging station is connected to the power grid. However, a longer charging
                    time, for example 6 hours, may be allowed on a stand-alone charging
                    station.</para>
            </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
    </para>
    <para/>
</chapter>

